Thomas Foxen Anderson Papers 1928-1989 Mss.Ms.Coll.75
American Philosophical Society
- Series IV. Works by Anderson, 1943-1985; 14 boxes; 6.5 linear feet
  Anderson's typewritten and handwritten outlines, preparatory notes, research, graphs and figures, drafts, and some galley proofs for articles. There are some notes for lectures, as well as several reviews of books. Some of the works are co-authored with colleagues and students. For each work, the notes and drafts are filed together. This series includes several early papers from the 1930s; the earliest is an article in German, "Ein Neues Drehprismenverfahren zur Photographischen Ermittlung der Dispersion. II. Mitteilung uber Refraktion und Dispersion von Kristallen," from 1935. There are also several historical treatments of electron microscopy, including "The First Years of the Electron Microscope in the United States, 1940-52," "Reflections on Phage Genetics," and Anderson's biographical memoir of Jack Schultz ("Jack Schultz, May 7, 1904 - April 29, 1971"). This series is arranged alphabetically by title, and cross references are given for photographs that appear in the series.
  - "The Action of an Antibiotic Substance (Penatin) on Bacteriophage", 1943 (Box 27)
  - "The Activation of Bacterial Viruses by Aromatic Amino Acids", 1945-1946 (Box 27)
  - "The Activation of the Bacterial Virus T4 by L-Tryptophan", [1948] (Box 27)
    -See also Ser.VII, same title
  - "The Activation of Viruses by Adsorption Cofactors", 1950 (Box 27)
    -See also Ser.I, Columbia University Press
    -See also Ser.I, The New York Academy of Medicine
  - "Activities in Microbiology at the Institute for Cancer Research", [1972] (Box 27)
  - "The Activity of a Bacteriostatic Substance in the Reaction Between Bacterial Virus and Host", [1945]; 2 folders (Box 27)
  - American Society for Microbiology--Lecture, 8 May 1962 (Box 27)
  - "Analyse de la Descendance de Zygotes Formés par Conjugaison chez Escherichia Coli K12"--with René Mazé, 1957 (Box 27)
  - "Appearance of Recombinants in Mixed Cultures of F- Escherichia Coli K-12" --with Jonathan T. Ou, 1978 (Box 27)
  - "The Application of Physical Chemistry to the Preparation of Specimens for Electron Microscopy"--Lecture, 7 Apr. 1972 (Box 27)
  - "The Application of the Electron Microscope to Biology", [1942] (Box 27)
  - "Applications of the Electron Microscope to Biology and Medicine" (Box 27)
  - "The Approximate Methods for the Calculation of Meridian Curves of Surfaces of Revolution", n.d. (Box 27)
  - "An Attempted Study of the Rate of Expansion of Lecithin Films at Constant Surface Pressures", 1938 (Box 27)
    -See also Ser.IV, "Protein Monolayers: Films of Oxidized Cytochrome C"
  - "The Bacterial Cell as Shown by the Electron Microscope"--with Stuart Mudd, H.E. Morton, and Katherine Polevitzky, 1942 (Box 27)
  - "Bacterial Morphology as Shown by the Electron Microsope. II. The Bacterial Cell Wall in the Genus Bacillus"--with Stuart Mudd, Katherine Polevitzky, and Leslie A. Chambers, 1940-1941 (Box 27)
  - "Bacterial Viruses - Structure and Function", [1959]; 3 folders (Box 28)
  - "Bacterial Viruses (1944-45)", 1945 (Box 28)
  - "A Bacteriolytic Element in a Purified Bacterial Virus", 17 Oct. 1944 (Box 28)
  - "A Bacteriolytic Substance Contained within a Purified Bacterial Virus", 17 Oct. 1944 (Box 28)
  - "Bacteriophage - The Virus Disease Agent of Bacteria"--Lecture at Sharp and Dohme, 9 Oct. 1944 (Box 28)
  - "Bacteriophage in Virus Vaccines" by J.C. Petricciani--Review, 14 Jun. 1973 (Box 28)
  - "Bacteriophages", [1950] (Box 28)
  - "Bacteriophages and Their Action on Host Cells", [1950] (Box 28)
  - "The Behavior of Color Film in the Electron Microscope", 1956 (Box 28)
  - Biological Abstracts--Review for, 7 Jan. 1943 (Box 28)
  - Biophysics Seminar, 1954-1955 (Box 28)
  - [Book Review], n.d. (Box 28)
  - "Chemical Structures of Co-Factors for Bacterial Viruses", [1945] (Box 28)
    -See also Ser.I, The Physiological Society of Philadelphia
  - Children's Hospital of Philadelphia--Lecture, 19 May 1944 (Box 28)
  - "Cofactors for Bacterial Viruses"--Lecture at Cold Spring Harbor, Summer 1945 (Box 28)
  - Cold Spring Harbor--Lectures, 1944, 1960, 1967 (Box 28)
  - "Composition of Growing Cell Cultures with Imperfect Inheritance"--with Edward Lustbader, 1975 (Box 28)
  - "Concerning the Effects of U.V. on Bacteria", 24 Mar. 1938 (Box 28)
  - "The Critical Point Method for Drying Electron Microscope Specimens: A Demonstration"--with Carl F. Oster, Jr., 5 Nov. 1953 (Box 28)
  - Dallas--Lecture, 29 Dec. 1941 (Box 28)
  - "Demonstration by the Electron Microscope of the Combination of Antibodies with Flagellar and Somatic Antigens"--with Stuart Mudd, 1941 (Box 28)
  - "The Denaturation and Coagulation of Native Proteins by Ultraviolet Light and by Heat", [193-] (Box 28)
  - "Destruction of Bacterial Viruses by Osmotic Shock", [1949] (Box 28)
  - "The Determination of Interfacial Tensions from the Study of Liquid Lenses", n.d. (Box 29)
  - "Diffraction from Helical Structure in Tail Sheaths of T-Even Bacteriophages"--with Sam Krimm, [196-] (Box 29)
  - "Diffraction of Light from Electron Micrographs"--Lecture at Philadelphia Electron Microscope Society, 25 Jun. 1965 (Box 29)
  - "Diffraction of Light from Electron Micrographs of Helical Structures in Bacteriophage Tail Sheaths"--with Sam Krimm, [1966] (Box 29)
  - "Discussion of the Morphology of Various Bacterial Forms, Some of Which Are of Pathogenic Significance in Oral Infections, as Shown by the Electron Microscope"--with Katherine A. Polevitzky (abstract), 1941 (Box 29)
  - "A Discussion of Techniques in the Preparation of Biological Specimens for Electron Microscopy", 1944 (Box 29)
  - "Doctor Leopold's Clinic"--Lecture, 6 Jun. 1944 (Box 29)
  - "The Effect of Colored Ions on the Photo-Inactivation of Invertase"--with Henry Lardy, 1942 (Box 29)
  - "Effect of Host Cell Wall Material on the Adsorbability of Cofactor-Requiring T4"--with Dennis T. Brown, [1969] (Box 29)
  - "The Effect of Sonic Vibration and Ultraviolet Light and pH on the Bacteriophage Virus", 1944 (Box 29)
  - "Effect of Zn2+ on Bacterial Conjugation: I. Inhibition of Mating Pair Formation"--with Jonathan T. Ou, 1972 (Box 29)
    -See also Ser.V, Ou, Jonathan T. Ou, "Effect of Zn2+ on Bacterial Conjugation: II. Increase in Ability of F- Cells to Form Mating Pairs"
  - "Effect of Zn2+ on the Adsorption of Male Specific Filamentous DNA and Isometric RNA Phages"--with Jonathan T. Ou, 1972 (Box 29)
  - "Effects of Brownian Motion on the Structure of a Three-Dimensional Specimen", 1952 (Box 29)
  - "The Effects of Heat and Ultraviolet Light on Certain Physiological Properties of Yeast"--with B.M. Duggar, [1941] (Box 29)
  - "Effects of Heat on Yeast. I. Rate of Death of Cells Which Survive Moderate Treatment"--with B.M. Duggar, 1938 (Box 29)
  - "Effects of Ultra-Violet Irradiation on Yeast: A Discussion and Explanation of Experiments Made Before February 1, 1938" (Box 29)
  - "Effects of Ultraviolet Light on the Crown Gall Organism", [193-] (Box 29)
  - "Effects of Violent Agitation on Adsorption of T4 Bacteriophage on Host Cells", 1947 (Box 29)
  - "Ein Neues Drehprismenverfahren zur Photographischen Ermittlung der Dispersion. II. Mitteilung uber Refraktion und Dispersion von Kristallen", 1935 (Box 29)
  - "Electron Micrograph Studies of Insect Structures"--with A. Glenn Richards, Jr. (abstract), 29 Dec. 1941 (Box 29)
  - "The Electron Micrography of Purified Viruses"--with Wendell M. Stanley (abstract) (Box 29)
  - "Electron Micrographs of Protein Molecules"--with Wendell M. Stanley, [1942] (Box 29)
  - "Electron Microscope Studies of Bacterial Viruses"--with Salvador E. Luria and Max Delbrück, [1943] (Box 29)
  - "Electron Microscope Studies of Bacteriophage"--Lecture, 19 Jan. 1943 (Box 29)
  - "Electron Microscope Studies of Squid Giant Nerve Axoplasm"--with A. Glenn Richards, Jr. and H. Burr Steinbach, [1943] (Box 29)
  - "The Electron Microscope - A New Instrument"--Lecture, n.d. (Box 29)
  - "The Electron Microscope and Philadelphia Bacteriology"--Lecture (Box 29)
  - "The Electron Microscope as a Research Tool in Biology and Medicine" (Box 29)
  - "The Electron Microscope as a Tool in Microbiology"--Lecture, 16 May 1968 (Box 29)
  - "The Electron Microscope in Medical Research", [1946] (Box 29)
  - "The Electron Microsope and Its Importance to Medicine"--Abstract, 1941 (Box 29)
  - "An Electron Microscope Study of Some Structural Colors of Insects"--with A. Glenn Richards, Jr., [1942] (Box 30)
  - "An Electron Microscope Study of the Digestion of E. Coli by Trypsin and Lysozyme"--with Carl F. Oster, Jr., [1954] (Box 30)
  - "An Electron Microscopic Study of the Precipitin Reaction", [196-] (Box 30)
  - "An Electron Microscopic Study of the Reaction Between Tobacco Mosaic Virus and Its Antiserum" (Box 30)
    -See Ser.IV, "A Study by Means of the Electron Microscope of the Reaction Between Tobacco Mosaic Virus and Its Antiserum"--with Wendell M. Stanley
  - "Electron Microscope Study of Bacteriophage"--Abstract, 26 Jan. 1943 (Box 30)
  - "Electron Microscopy of Microorganisms", 1953-1956; 5 folders (Box 30)
  - "Electron Microscopy of Phages", 1966; 2 folders (Box 30)
  - "Electron Microscopy Then and Now: Forty Years of Research on the Structure of Microorganisms"--Lecture, 28 Apr. 1980 (Box 30)
  - "Electron Microscopy"--Lecture at University of Pennsylvania Department of Physics, Apr. 1977 (Box 30)
  - "F1 Plasmids from HfrH and HfrC in recA- Escherichia Coli"--with Jonathan T. Ou, 1974-1975; 2 folders (Box 31)
  - "The First Years of the Electron Microscope in the United States, 1940-52", [1985] (Box 31)
  - "Fractionation of Shope Papilloma Virus in Cesium Chloride Density Gradients"--with Charles Breedis, 1962 (Box 31)
  - "Functional Anatomy of Bacteriophage Particles"--with Dennis T. Brown and Lee D. Simon (Box 31)
  - "Further Electron Microscope Studies on Arthropod Tracheae"--with A. Glenn Richards, Jr., [1942] (Box 31)
  - "Further Studies of Population Dynamics of Cultured Cells"--with Edward Lustbader, [197-]; 3 folders (Box 31)
    -See also Ser.IV, "Population Genetics of Asexual Organisms"
  - "Genetic Exchange Between Two Sex Factor-Less E. Coli Strains"--with Jonathan T. Ou (Box 31)
    -See Ser.IV, "Appearance of Recombinants in Mixed Cultures of F- Escherichia Coli K-12"--with Jonathan T. Ou
  - "Genetic Exchange Occurs in Mixed Cultures of F- Strains of Escherichia Coli K-12", 1978; 3 folders (Box 31)
    - Folder #1--Ms., 1978 (Box 31)
    - Folder #2--Notebook, 1978 (Box 31)
    - Folder #3--Notes, 1978 (Box 31)
  - "Genetics of the P22 - P221 System"--with Nobuto Yamamoto, M.J. Kushmerick, Jr., and Donald H. Walker, Jr., 1961 (Box 31)
  - General Electric Company--Lecture, 25 Aug. 1942 (Box 31)
  - "Genomic Masking and Recombination Between Serologically Unrelated Phages P22 and P221"--with Nobuto Yamamoto, 1961 (Box 32)
    -See also Ser.I, Eisenstark, Abe
    -See also Ser.I, Hartman, Philip
    -See also Ser.I, Hershey, Alfred
    -See also Ser.I, Jacob, François
    -See also Ser.VII, "Genomic Masking and Recombination Between Serologically Unrelated Phages P22 and P221"
  - "The Growth of T2 Virus on Ultraviolet-Killed Host Cells", [1948]; 2 folders (Box 32)
  - "The Identification and Characterization of Bacteriophages with the Electron Microscope"--with Salvador E. Luria, [1942] (Box 32)
  - "Identification of Poliovirus Particles of Different Antigenicity by Specific Agglutination as Seen in the Electron Microscope"--with Klaus Hummeler and Raymond A. Brown, 1961-1962 (Box 32)
    -See also Ser.I, Hummeler, Klaus, 11 Jul. 1961
    -See also Ser.VII, "Identification of Poliovirus Particles of Different Antigenicity by Specific Agglutination as Seen in the Electron Microscope"
  - "In Vitro Formation of Infectious Particles from Heads and Base Plate Parts of Phage 22"--with J.V. Israel and M. Levine (Abstract), 1966 (Box 32)
  - "In Vitro Morphogenesis of Phage P22 from Heads and Base-Plate Parts"--with J.V. Israel and Myron Levine, 1967 (Box 32)
  - "The Inactivation of a Bacterial Virus by a Preparation of Penatin Derived from Penicillium Notatum" (Box 32)
    -See Ser.IV, "The Action of an Antibiotic Substance (Penatin) on Bacteriophage"
  - "The Influence of Temperature and Nutrients on Plaque Formation by Bacteriophages Active on Escherichia Coli Strain B", [1948] (Box 32)
  - "Inheritability of Plasmids and Population Dynamics of Cultured Cells", 1975; 2 folders (Box 32)
  - "Inheritance in Families of Bacteria"--with René Mazé, [195-] (Box 32)
  - "The Inheritance of Requirements for Adsorption Cofactors in the Bacterial Virus T4", [1948] (Box 33)
  - "Inhibition of Mating Pair Formation by Type I Pili"--with Jonathan T. Ou, [1972] (Box 33)
  - "An Instrument for Continuously Recording the Concentration of Nitrogen in Gas Mixtures"--with John C. Lilly and John P. Hervey, 1946 (Box 33)
  - International Organization for Pure and Applied Biophysics--Meeting Account, [1964] (Box 33)
    -See also Ser.I, Science
  - "The Intracellular Growth of Bacteriophages. II. The Growth of T3 Studied by Sonic Disintegration and by T6-Cyanide Lysis of Infected Cells"--with A.H. Doermann, [1952] (Box 33)
  - "Introduction to Symposium on the Structures of Viruses", May 1962 (Box 33)
  - "Jack Schultz, May 7, 1904 - April 29, 1971", 1961-1975; 5 folders (Box 33)
    -See also Ser.I, Bayer, Margret
    -See also Ser.I, Cohen, Leonard
    -See also Ser.I, Hungerford, David
    -See also Ser.I, Perry, Robert P.
    -See also Ser.VII, "Jack Schultz, May 7, 1904 - April 29, 1971"
    Biographical and personal data -- Schultz, Jack; Columbia University; Cytogenetics; Drosophila genetics; Morgan, Thomas Hunt; Publication -- Genetics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Folder #1, 1972 (Box 33)
    - Folder #2, 1972-1973 (Box 33)
    - Folder #3, 1973 (Box 33)
    - Folder #4, 1975 (Box 33)
    - Research Materials, 1961-1971 (Box 33)
  - Johns Hopkins University--Biophysics Seminar, 21 Oct. 1955 (Box 34)
  - Johnson Foundation--Seminars, 1945, 1947, 1958 (Box 34)
  - [Life], n.d. (Box 34)
  - Lectures, 1959-1961 (Box 34)
  - "Liquid Lenses", n.d. (Box 34)
  - "Location of F Pili Gene and Differences Between HfrH and HfrC"--with Jonathan T. Ou, [1971] (Box 34)
  - Marine Biological Laboratory--Lecture, Jul 1942 (Box 34)
  - "Mechanism of Viral Infections"--Lecture, 6 Nov. 1962 (Box 34)
  - "Medical Criticism and Statistics"--Lectures, 1950 (Box 34)
  - "A Method for Eliminating Gross Artefacts in Drying Specimens", 1950-1952 (Box 34)
  - "Methods for Determining the Number of Particles Necessary to Infect"--Lecture, 1955 (Box 34)
  - "Microscopie Électronique sur Film en Couleurs Ektachrome Lumière du Jour", [1956] (Box 34)
    In French
  - "A Mirror Spectroscope for Visible and Ultra-Violet Light; the Refractive Index of Caesium Chloride"--with Peter Wulff (Box 34)
    -See Ser.IV, "Ein Neues Drehprismenverfahren zur Photographischen Ermittlung der Dispersion. II. Mitteilung uber Refraktion und Dispersion von Kristallen"
  - [Modern Science], n.d. (Box 34)
  - "Molecular Biology of Bacteriophages"--University of Pennsylvania Physics Colloqium, 11 Dec. 1968 (Box 34)
  - "The Molecular Organization of Virus Particles", [1967] (Box 34)
  - "Molecular Structures of Bacteria and Bacteriophages" (Box 34)
  - "Morphological Structure of Rickettsiae"--with Harry Plotz, Joseph E. Smadel, and Leslie A. Chambers, 1942-1943 (Box 34)
  - "Morphological Structure of the Virus of Vaccinia"--with R.H. Green and Joseph E. Smadel, 1942 (Box 34)
  - "Morphological Variants of Coliphage P1"--with Donald H. Walker, Jr., [1970] (Box 34)
  - "Morphological Variants of the Bacteriophage P1"--with Donald H. Walker, Jr., [1960] (Box 34)
    -See also Ser.II, National Academy of Sciences
    -See also Ser.VII, "Morphological Variants of the Bacteriophage P1"
  - "Morphologies of Bacteriophage Virions", 1971-1972 (Box 34)
  - "The Morphology and Osmotic Properties of Bacteriophage Systems", [1953] (Box 34)
  - National Science Foundation Academic Year Institute--Lecture at University of Pennsylvania, 7 Nov. 1962 (Box 34)
  - "The Nature of Viruses", n.d. (Box 34)
  - "Nature Through the Electron Microscope"--with A. Glenn Richards, Jr., [1942] (Box 34)
  - "Negative Staining and Its Use in the Study of Viruses and Their Serological Reactions", 1962 (Box 34)
  - "A New Technique for the Study of Biological Structures in the Electron Microscope", 23 Jun. 1950 (Box 34)
  - "A Nitrogen Meter for Continuously Recording the Concentration of Nitrogen in Gas Mixtures"--with John C. Lilly and John P. Hervey (Box 34)
    -See Ser.IV, "An Instrument for Continuously Recording the Concentration of Nitrogen in Gas Mixtures"--with John C. Lilly and John P. Hervey
  - "Observations on the Morphology of Leptospira and the Nichols' Strain of Treponema Pallidum with the Aid of the RCA Electron Microscope"--Abstract (Box 35)
  - "On a Bacteriolytic Substance Associated with a Purified Bacterial Virus", [1944] (Box 35)
  - "On Determinants of Bilateral Symmetry in Higher Organisms" (Box 35)
  - "On the Fine Structures of the Temperate Bacteriophages P1, P2 and P22", [1960] (Box 35)
    -See also Ser.I, European Regional Conference on Electron Microscopy
    -See also Ser.VII, "On the Fine Structures of the Temperate Bacteriophages P1, P2 and P22"
  - "On the Inheritability of Plasmids and the Population Dynamics of Cultured Cells"--with Edward Lustbader, 1975; 2 folders (Box 35)
    -See also Ser.I, Crow, James F.
    -See also Ser.VII, "On the Inheritability of Plasmids and the Population Dynamics of Cultured Cells"
  - "On the Mechanism of Adsorption of Bacteriophages on Host Cells", [1949] (Box 35)
  - "On the Mechanism of Virus Multiplication II. The Ultraviolet Irradiation of Infected Host Cells During Growth of Virus", 1943, 1946 (Box 35)
  - "On the Mechanism of Virus Multiplication" (Box 35)
    -See Ser.IV, "The Growth of T2 Virus on Ultraviolet-Killed Host Cells"
  - "On the Nature of the Viral Infective Particle" (Box 35)
    -See Ser.IV, "Remarques sur les Caracteristiques de la Particule Virale Infectieuse"--with André Lwoff and François Jacob
  - "On the Structure and Osmotic Properties of Phage Particles"--with Catherine Rappaport and Naomi M. Muscatine, [1953] (Box 35)
  - "The Organization of Viruses"--Lecture, 22 Jun. 1967 (Box 35)
  - "On the Structure of Compounds Which Promote the Activity of Bacterial Viruses" (Box 35)
    -See Ser.IV, "The Activity of a Bacteriostatic Substance in the Reaction Between Bacterial Virus and Host"
  - "An Outline of Chemical and Statistical Thermodynamics" (Box 35)
  - "Parapatetic Clubs"--Lecture, 8 Feb. 1947 (Box 35)
  - "Pedigrees of Exconjugants in Escherichia Coli K12", [1957] (Box 35)
  - "The Persistence of the Effects of Heat on the Visibility of the Yeast Saccharomyces Cerevisiae in Various Salt Solutions"--with B.M. Duggar, 1938 (Box 35)
  - Philadelphia Electron Microscope Society--Lecture, 5 Apr. 1951 (Box 35)
  - "Physical Methods of Characterizing Virus Particles", 1960-1961 (Box 35)
  - "Physical Properties of Viruses"--Lecture, 1946-1970 (Box 35)
  - "Physical Structure of Viruses I"--Lecture, 8 Oct. 1970 (Box 35)
  - Physics Seminar, Botany Seminar, 4 Dec. 1946, 10 Jan. 1947 (Box 35)
  - The Physics of Viruses by Ernest C. Pollard--Review, 1953 (Box 35)
  - "Population Genetics of Asexual Organisms"--with Edward Lustbader, [197-] (Box 36)
    -See also Ser.IV, "Further Studies of Population Dynamics of Cultured Cells"
  - "The Preparation of Holey Films for Electron Microscopy"--with Manfred E. Bayer, 1962 (Box 36)
    -See also Ser.I, Nature, 14 Nov. 1962
    -See also Ser.VII, "The Preparation of Holey Films for Electron Microscopy"
  - "Preservation of Structure in Dried Specimens", Jul 1954 (Box 36)
  - Princeton University--Lectures, 1940-1941 (Box 36)
  - "The Problem of the Intensities of Vibrational Lines in the Raman Spectra of Diatomic Molecules", [1940] (Box 36)
  - Proceedings of the First International Congress of Electron Microscopy--Review, 1953 (Box 36)
  - "Progress Report of Studies on the Effects of Radiation on Microorganisms"--with B.M. Duggar, Apr. 1939 (Box 36)
  - "Propagation and Genetics of Bacteriophages"--Lecture, 1952 (Box 36)
  - "Protein Monolayers: Films of Oxidized Cytochrome C"--with William D. Harkins, [1938] (Box 36)
    -See also Ser.IV, "An Attempted Study of the Rate of Expansion of Lecithin Films at Constant Surface Pressures"
  - "Quantitative Cell Biophysics", 1980 (Box 36)
  - "Racemases", 1973 (Box 36)
  - "The Raman Spectra and Molecular Constants of Phosphorous Trifluoride and Phosphine"--with Don M. Yost, 1934 (Box 36)
  - "The Raman Spectrum of Boron Trifluoride Gas"--with Don M. Yost, Don Devault, and Edwin N. Lasettre, [1938] (Box 36)
    -See also Ser.V, Yost, Don M., "The Raman Spectrum of Boron Trifluoride"
    -See also Ser.VII, "The Raman Spectrum of Boron Trifluoride Gas"
  - "The Raman Spectrum of Deuterium", 1935 (Box 36)
  - "The Raman Spectrum of Liquid Diborane"--with Anton B. Burg. Folder #1, [1938] (Box 36)
  - "The Raman Spectrum of Liquid Diborane"--with Anton B. Burg. Folder #2, [1938] (Box 36)
  - "The Raman Spectrum of Tetraethyl Silane. Vibrational Resonance of Tetraalkyls", [1936] (Box 36)
  - "The Rates of Deactivation and Adsorption on Its Host of Tryptophane-Activated T4 Bacteriophage", 1947-1948 (Box 36)
  - "The Reactions of Bacterial Viruses with Their Host Cells", [1949] (Box 36)
  - "Recent Developments in the Structure and Function of Bacteriophage", 1960 or 1961 (Box 36)
  - "Recent Developments in the Structure and Function of Bacteriophage"--Lecture, 20 Jan. 1960 (Box 36)
  - "Recombination and Segregation in Bacterial Zygotes"--Abstract, Feb. 1958 (Box 37)
  - "Recombination and Segregation in Escherichia Coli", 1958 (Box 37)
    -See also Ser.II, Long Island Biological Association
  - "Recombination as Studied by Pedigrees of Bacteria after Conjugation"--Abstract, 1958 (Box 37)
  - "Recombination: P22 and P221", 1962-1963 (Box 37)
    -See also Ser.I, Yamamoto, Nobuto, 1962-1963
    -See also Ser.VII, "Recombination: P22 and P221"
  - "Reflections on Phage Genetics", 1981; 2 folders (Box 37)
    -See also Ser.I, Annual Review of Genetics
  - "Remarques sur les Caracteristiques de la Particule Virale Infectieuse"--with André Lwoff and François Jacob, 1958-1959 (Box 37)
  - "Report on Effects of Radiation on Phytomonas Tumefaciens", 31 mar. 1938 (Box 37)
  - "Report on the Annual Meeting of the German Society for Electron Microscopy"--with Ralph W.G. Wyckoff, 1953 (Box 37)
  - "Report on Visit to England and France, April 1949" (Box 37)
  - "Results of E.M. Studies of Bacteriophage"--Lecture, 11 Jun. 1948 (Box 37)
  - "Role of Pili in Bacterial Conjugation"--with Jonathan T. Ou, 1970 (Box 37)
  - "The Role of the Electron Microscope in Virus Research"--Lecture, 4 Mar. 1953 (Box 37)
  - "The Role of Tryptophane in the Adsorption of Two Bacterial Viruses on Their Host, E. Coli", [1945] (Box 37)
  - Saint Louis--Lecture, n.d. (Box 37)
  - "Selective 'Staining' for Electron Micrography"--with Stuart Mudd, 1942 (Box 37)
  - "Serial Sections for Electron Microscopy"--with Helen Gay, 1954 (Box 37)
  - "A Shadow-Casting Adaptor for the Electron Microscope", 1946 (Box 37)
  - "The Shadow-Casting Technique in Electron Microscopy"--Abstract, 1946 (Box 37)
  - "A Simple Accurate Film Balance of the Vertical Type for Biological and Chemical Work, and a Theoretical and Experimental Comparison with the Horizontal Type. II. Tight Packing of a Monolayer by Ions"--with William D. Harkins, [1937] (Box 38)
  - "Some Biochemical Applications of the Electron Microscope", n.d. (Box 38)
  - "Some Chemical Applications of Raman Spectra", 15 Jun. 1940 (Box 38)